Muhammad Jawad

Software Engineer

Personal details



Muhammad Jawad



jawaddmuhammad@gmail.com



03034094558



H#207A, Muslim Street, Yasrab Colony Baghat Pura Shadbagh 54900 Lahore



May 22, 2000



linkedin.com/in/M-Jawad-Malik



github.com/M-Jawad-Malik

Skills

Research Article Writing

Technical Business Writing

Critical thinking

Collaborative

C++ programming

Python

Understanding of ML Algorithms

Networking on Cisco Packet Tracer

Client Side Web Development

HTML, CSS, Javascript

.Net Framwork

Windows Form Application

MERN Stack Development

Database Management

MS SQL Server

MS SQL, PostgreSQL

Android Application Development (Java)

Objective

Software development professional with a passion to learn and implement new technologies and a great eye for design and client expectations. Determined to develop quality software, fully satisfying clients. Possessing many skills, I want to enhance my experience in the field as a software engineer.

Experience

Teacher (Computer Science) TIMS ACADEMY, Lahore	Jun 2019 - Mar 2020
Desktop App Developer Self-Employed, Lahore	Jun 2020 - Apr 2021
Teacher (Computer Science) IDEAL ACADEMY OF COMPUTER SCIENCE, LAhore	Nov 2020 - Nov 2021
Teacher Assistant (.Net Framework) Lahore Garrison University, Lahore	Oct 2021 - May 2022
Software Engineer Mindstormerz Studio : Part-time, Lahore	Jan 2022 - May 2022
Home Tutor (C++) Divines Garden New Airport Road Lahore, Lahore	Jan 2022 - Present

May 2022 - Oct 2022

Projects

Developer)

Face Recognition using Clarifai Face Detection API

Software Engineer (Web & Mobile App

INGENDEV Tech Solutions: Part-time, Lahore

INGENDEV Tech Solutions, Lahore

Project Developed to Detect Faces in Picture using Clarifai Face Detection API.

Robo Friends

INGENDEV Tech Solutions, Lahore

Developed on ReactJS, crux of idea was showing info of robots with their images using random number, generated through Robo Hash API.

Final Year Project

Associated with Lahore Garrison University

Titled as "IOT based Housing Society Automation", the project was developed on a networking simulation tool i.e. cisco packet tracer. In addition to this an android app "TriS App" was developed: a society specific app focused to provide ease of doing business in society, connecting society businesses with residents and society management with residents and businesses.

Resort Android App

INGENDEV Tech Solutions, Lahore

An Android developed for the ease of booking tours and searching and contacting the Tour Guider.

Freight Movers LLC Web Project

Associated with INGENDEV

A static website developed for client hosted on hostinger with domain on hostinger with custom emails.

Languages

Punjabi (Native)

English (Conversational)

Urdu (Native)

Certificates

Robotics Course

May 2019

LEGO Workshop attendee

Jun 2019

Python Fundamentals Trainer

Apr 2020

NumPy Workshop Trainer

Jun 2020

FYP Showcase Certificate

Oct 2022

Highest GPA Award

Jun 2022

Achievements

- FYP nominated for Final Year Project Showcase held in University.
- FYP nominated for upcoming PHEC FYP Showcase at Flattie's Hotel on Nov 15 2022.
- Lead a team that achieved the highest score in organizing workshops as part of Business Subject.

Link: www.freightmoversllc.us

An IOT based Housing Society Automation with Packet Tracer using VLSM Technique

Associated with LAHORE GARRISON UNIVERSITY

A research paper based on networking concept of VLSM (variable length subnet mask), in which core concept was how we can centeralize asset control of residential societies using iot devices like smart cities & smart homes.

Installment Shop Desktop Application

Self-Employed, Lahore

Desktop Application developed on .Net Framework, for an Installment shop owner that manages their stock, installments, payments and earnings records.

deServico Android App with Web Messenger

Associated with LAHORE GARRISON UNIVERSITY

A semester project as a single group member I developed an android app throgh which user can hire service provider. Both stakeholders can track each others location which was achieved using Google Map API. App was developed in Kotlin, Consist of a messenger through which both of the stakeholders can communicate with each other. In addition to this i developed a web messenger too that is integrated with the android app through firebase realtime database and for web Azure Hosting was used.

An Enhanced Median Based Round Robin Algorithm for CPU Scheduling with Context Switch Sorting

Associated with LAHORE GARRISON UNIVERSITY

A research based semester project of Operating System in which me with a group of 4 has to find out a variant of Round Robin Algorithm for CPU sceduling.

For More Projects you can check my linkedin profile.

Education

Software Engineering - Bachelor Sep 2018 - Oct 2022

Lahore Garrison University, Lahore, Punjab

CGPA:3.79

FSc Pre Engineering - Intermediate Sep 2016 - Sep 2018

Govt. Islamia College Civil Lines, Lahore, Punjab

Marks: 75%

Matriculation Apr 2014 - Jul 2016

Govt. High School Shadbagh Lahore, Lahore, Punjab

Marks: 91%

References

References available upon request.